<metadata>  <idinfo>    <citation>      <citeinfo>        <origin>Wildland Fire Science, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center, U.S. Geological Survey</origin>        <pubdate>20130331</pubdate>        <pubtime>unknown</pubtime>        <title>LANDFIRE.US_130EVC</title>        <geoform>map</geoform>        <serinfo>          <sername>LANDFIRE Existing Vegetation Cover</sername>          <issue>LANDFIRE 2012 (lf_1.3.0)</issue>        </serinfo>        <pubinfo>          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>          <publish>Wildland Fire Science, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center, U.S. Geological Survey</publish>        </pubinfo>        <othercit>United States Forest Service</othercit>        <onlink>http://landfire.cr.usgs.gov/viewer/</onlink>        <onlink>http://www.landfire.gov</onlink>      </citeinfo>    </citation>    <descript>      <abstract>Introduction: The LANDFIRE existing vegetation layers describe the following elements of existing vegetation for each LANDFIRE mapping zone: existing vegetation type, existing vegetation canopy cover, and existing vegetation height. Vegetation is mapped using predictive landscape models based on extensive field reference data, satellite imagery, biophysical gradient layers, and classification and regression trees. Abstract: The existing vegetation cover (EVC) data layer depicts percent canopy cover by life form, and is an important input to other LANDFIRE mapping efforts. EVC is generated separately for tree, shrub and herbaceous life forms using training data and a series of geospatial predictor layers. Plots from the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program of USDA Forest Service (http://fia.fs.fed.us/) were used as the training data for tree canopy cover mapping, with canopy cover of the plots estimated from stem-mapped tree data and calibrated with line intercept field measurements of canopy cover (Toney and others 2009). Shrub and herbaceous canopy cover training data were also derived from plot-level, ground-based visual assessments. More information regarding contributors of field plot data can be found athttp://www.landfire.gov/participate_acknowledgements.php. Regression tree models were developed separately for each life form using the training data and a combination of multitemporal Landsat data, terrain data from a digital elevation model, and biophysical gradient data layers. Cubist software was used for modeling. The derived regression tree equations were then applied to the geospatial predictor data to create 30-m resolution, life form specific data layers (i.e., separate data layers are generated for tree, shrub and herbaceous vegetation cover). Each of the derived data layers (tree, shrub, herbaceous) has a potential range of 0-100 percent canopy cover. Tree, shrub and herbaceous values were binned into discrete classes (up to 10 bins at 10 percent intervals for tree, shrub and herbaceous canopy cover). The final EVC layer was evaluated and rectified through a series of QA/QC measures to ensure that the life form of the canopy cover code matched the life form of the LANDFIRE existing vegetation type (EVT) layer. EVC is used in the development of subsequent LANDFIRE data layers.LF 2012 (lf_1.3.0) used modified LF 2010 (lf_1.2.0) data as a launching point to incorporate disturbance and its severity, both managed and natural, which occurred on the landscape 2011 and 2012. Specific examples of disturbance are: fire, vegetation management, weather, and insect and disease. The final disturbance data used in LANDFIRE is the result of several efforts that include data derived in part from remotely sensed land change methods, Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity (MTBS), and the LANDFIRE Events data call. Vegetation growth was modeled where both disturbance and non-disturbance occurs.Urban, agriculture, and wetlands were refined to reflect a 2012 landscape using the National Conservation Easement Database, National Wetlands Inventory (NWI), and Common Land Unit database (CLU) data.</abstract>      <purpose>LANDFIRE data products are designed to facilitate national- and regional-level strategic planning and reporting of management activities. Data products are created at a 30-meter grid spatial resolution raster data set; however, the applicability of data products varies by location and specific use. Principal purposes of the data products include providing, 1) national-level, landscape-scale geospatial products to support fire and fuels management planning, and, 2) consistent fuels data to support fire planning, analysis, and budgeting to evaluate fire management alternatives. Users are advised to evaluate the data carefully for their applications.</purpose><supplinf></supplinf>    </descript>    <status>      <progress>Complete</progress>      <update>None planned</update>    </status>    <spdom>      <bounding><westbc>-82.9568157727</westbc><eastbc>-82.2753234638</eastbc><northbc>41.5462208014</northbc><southbc>41.2156040825</southbc></bounding>    </spdom>    <keywords>      <theme>        <themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt>        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>        <themekey>010</themekey>      </theme>      <theme>        <themekt>None</themekt>        <themekey>Raster digital data</themekey>        <themekey>LF_1.3.0</themekey>        <themekey>LANDFIRE</themekey>        <themekey>USFS</themekey>        <themekey>GIS</themekey>        <themekey>LANDFIRE 2012</themekey>        <themekey>United States Forest Service</themekey>        <themekey>USGS</themekey>        <themekey>Existing Vegetation Cover</themekey>        <themekey>EVC</themekey>        <themekey>U.S. Geological Survey</themekey>      </theme>      <place>        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard 10-4,): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>        <placekey>US</placekey>        <placekey>United States</placekey>        <placekey>U.S.</placekey>      </place>    </keywords>    <accconst>None</accconst>    <useconst>Although LANDFIRE products are delivered as 30-meter pixels, they should not be used at the individual pixel level or on small groups of pixels. LANDFIRE products were designed to support 1) national (all states) strategic planning, 2) regional (single large states or groups of smaller states), and 3) strategic/tactical planning for large sub-regional landscapes and Fire Management Units (FMUs) (such as significant portions of states or multiple federal administrative entities). The applicability of LANDFIRE products to support fire and land management planning on smaller areas will vary by product, location, and specific use. Further investigation by local and regional experts should be conducted to inform decisions regarding local applicability. However, it is the responsibility of the local user, using LANDFIRE metadata and local knowledge, to determine if and/or how LANDFIRE can be used for particular areas of interest. LANDFIRE products are not intended to replace local products, but rather serve as a back-up by providing wall-to-wall cross-boundary products. It is the responsibility of the user to be familiar with the value, assumptions, and limitations of LANDFIRE products. Managers and planners must evaluate LANDFIRE data according to the scale and requirements specific to their needs.</useconst>    <ptcontac>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>Wildland Fire Science, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center, U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntpos>Customer Service Representative</cntpos>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>physical</addrtype>          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>          <city>Sioux Falls</city>          <state>SD</state>          <postal>57198-0001</postal>          <country>US</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>605/594-6151</cntvoice>        <cntfax>605/594-6589</cntfax>        <cntemail>helpdesk@landfire.gov</cntemail>      </cntinfo>    </ptcontac>    <datacred>Data have been collected and analyzed by teams at both USGS EROS, Sioux Falls, SD and at the USFS, Rocky Mountain Research Station, Missoula, MT. Depending on the data set described primary responsibility may reside with USGS EROS or with USFS. Contact information will be listed in the Contact Section and in the Metadata Reference section with regards to the primary responsibility.</datacred>    <secinfo>      <secsys>None in place</secsys>      <secclass>Unclassified</secclass>      <sechandl>If there is ever doubt, contact the appropriate resource staff who has stewardship responsibility and the GIS Coordinator.</sechandl>    </secinfo>    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.722</native>    <crossref>      <citeinfo>        <origin>Toney, Chris; Shaw, John D.; Nelson, Mark D.</origin>        <pubdate>20090101</pubdate>        <title>A stem-map model for predicting tree canopy cover of Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) plots</title>        <othercit>RMRS-P-56CD. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 19 p.</othercit>        <onlink>http://www.treesearch.fs.fed.us/pubs/33381</onlink>      </citeinfo>    </crossref>  </idinfo>  <dataqual>    <lineage>      <procstep>        <procdesc>For a detailed definition and discussion on LANDFIRE, refer to http://www.LANDFIRE.gov</procdesc>        <procdate>unknown</procdate>        <proccont>          <cntinfo>            <cntorgp>              <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>            </cntorgp>            <cntpos>Customer Service Representative</cntpos>            <cntaddr>              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>              <address>47914 252nd Street</address>              <address>USGS EROS</address>              <city>Sioux Falls</city>              <state>SD</state>              <postal>57198-0001</postal>              <country>US</country>            </cntaddr>            <cntvoice>605/594-6151</cntvoice>            <cnttdd>605/594-6933</cnttdd>            <cntfax>605/594-6589</cntfax>            <cntemail>custserv@usgs.gov</cntemail>            <hours>0800 - 1600, CT M-F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</hours>          </cntinfo>        </proccont>      </procstep>      <procstep>        <procdesc>LANDFIRE Refresh 2001 (lf_1.0.5): Imagery used in LANDFIRE National covered a span of years and several large wildland fires may not be represented for the time period used in that locale. LANDFIRE circa 2001 ensures wildland fires through 2001 are represented. Additional improvements implemented in Refresh 2001 include resolving inconsistencies along the international borders and updating aspects of the following: riparian and wetlands areas, agricultural and urban vegetation types as burnable, and adjusting the extent of barren and water land cover types.</procdesc>        <procdate>20110214</procdate>      </procstep>      <procstep>        <procdesc>Metadata updated</procdesc>        <procdate>20111208</procdate>      </procstep>    </lineage>  </dataqual>  <spdoinfo>    <rastinfo>      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>      <rowcount>996</rowcount>      <colcount>1763</colcount>      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>    </rastinfo>  </spdoinfo>  <eainfo>    <detailed>      <enttyp>        <enttypl>evc</enttypl>        <enttypd>Existing Vegetation Cover</enttypd>        <enttypds>Landfire</enttypds>      </enttyp>      <attr>        <attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Existing vegetation cover</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>11</edomv>            <edomvd>Open Water</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>12</edomv>            <edomvd>Snow/Ice</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>13</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Upland Deciduous Forest</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>14</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Upland Evergreen Forest</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>15</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Upland Mixed Forest</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>16</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Upland Herbaceous</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>17</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Upland Shrubland</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>18</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Herbaceous Wetland Vegetation</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>19</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Woody Wetland Vegetation</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>20</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed - General</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>21</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed - Open Space</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>22</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed - Low Intensity</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>23</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed - Medium Intensity</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>24</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed - High Intensity</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>25</edomv>            <edomvd>Developed-Roads</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>31</edomv>            <edomvd>Barren</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>32</edomv>            <edomvd>Quarries-Strip Mines-Gravel Pits</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>60</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Orchard</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>61</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Vineyard</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>62</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Bush fruit and berries</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>63</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Row Crop-Close Grown Crop</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>64</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Row Crop</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>65</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Close Grown Crop</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>66</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Pasture and Hayland</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>67</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Pasture and Hayland</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>          <edom>            <edomv>68</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS-Wheat</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>          <edom>            <edomv>69</edomv>            <edomvd>NASS - Aquaculture</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>75</edomv>            <edomvd>Herbaceous Semi-dry</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>76</edomv>            <edomvd>Herbaceous Semi-wet</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>78</edomv>            <edomvd>Recently Disturbed Forest</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>80</edomv>            <edomvd>Agriculture - General</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>81</edomv>            <edomvd>Pasture/Hay</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>82</edomv>            <edomvd>Cultivated Crops</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>83</edomv>            <edomvd>Small Grains</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>84</edomv>            <edomvd>Fallow</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>85</edomv>            <edomvd>Urban-Recreational Grasses</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>95</edomv>            <edomvd>Herbaceous Wetlands</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>100</edomv>            <edomvd>Sparse Vegetation Canopy</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>101</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>102</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>103</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>104</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>105</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>106</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>107</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>108</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>109</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>111</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>112</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>113</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>114</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>115</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>116</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>117</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>118</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>119</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>121</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>122</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>123</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>124</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>125</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>126</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>127</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>128</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>129</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>150</edomv>            <edomvd>Sparse Vegetation Canopy</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>151</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 25%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>152</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Canopy &gt;= 25 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>153</edomv>            <edomvd>Tree Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>161</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 25%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>162</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Canopy &gt;= 25 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>163</edomv>            <edomvd>Shrub Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>171</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 60%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>        <attrdomv>          <edom>            <edomv>172</edomv>            <edomvd>Herb Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%</edomvd>            <edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>          </edom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Count</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Number of pixels</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Evc_name</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Existing vegetation cover name</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>R</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Red color value</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>G</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Green color value</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>B</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Blue color value</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Red</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Red color value/255</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Green</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Green color value/255</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>      <attr>        <attrlabl>Blue</attrlabl>        <attrdef>Blue color value/255</attrdef>        <attrdefs>Landfire</attrdefs>        <attrdomv>          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>        </attrdomv>      </attr>    </detailed>    <overview>      <eaover>VALUE	CLASSNAMES11	Open Water12	Snow/Ice13	Developed-Upland Deciduous Forest14	Developed-Upland Evergreen Forest15	Developed-Upland Mixed Forest16	Developed-Upland Herbaceous17	Developed-Upland Shrubland18	Developed-Herbaceous Wetland Vegetation19	Developed-Woody Wetland Vegetation20	Developed - General21	Developed - Open Space22	Developed - Low Intensity23	Developed - Medium Intensity24	Developed - High Intensity25	Developed-Roads31	Barren32	Quarries-Strip Mines-Gravel Pits60	NASS-Orchard61	NASS-Vineyard62	NASS-Bush fruit and berries63	NASS-Row Crop-Close Grown Crop64	NASS-Row Crop65	NASS-Close Grown Crop66	NASS-Fallow/Idle Cropland67	NASS-Pasture and Hayland68           NASS - Wheat69           NASS-Aquaculture75	Herbaceous Semi-dry76	Herbaceous Semi-wet78	Recently Disturbed Forest80	Agriculture - General81	Pasture/Hay82	Cultivated Crops83	Small Grains84	Fallow85	Urban-Recreational Grasses95	Herbaceous Wetlands100	Sparse Vegetation Canopy101	Tree Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%102	Tree Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%103	Tree Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%104	Tree Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%105	Tree Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%106	Tree Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%107	Tree Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%108	Tree Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%109	Tree Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%111	Shrub Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%112	Shrub Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%113	Shrub Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%114	Shrub Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%115	Shrub Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%116	Shrub Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%117	Shrub Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%118	Shrub Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%119	Shrub Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%121	Herb Cover &gt;= 10 and &lt; 20%122	Herb Cover &gt;= 20 and &lt; 30%123	Herb Cover &gt;= 30 and &lt; 40%124	Herb Cover &gt;= 40 and &lt; 50%125	Herb Cover &gt;= 50 and &lt; 60%126	Herb Cover &gt;= 60 and &lt; 70%127	Herb Cover &gt;= 70 and &lt; 80%128	Herb Cover &gt;= 80 and &lt; 90%129	Herb Cover &gt;= 90 and &lt;= 100%150	Sparse Vegetation Canopy151	Tree Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 25%152	Tree Canopy &gt;= 25 and &lt; 60%153	Tree Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%161	Shrub Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 25%162	Shrub Canopy &gt;= 25 and &lt; 60%163	Shrub Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%171	Herb Canopy &gt;= 10 and &lt; 60%172	Herb Canopy &gt;= 60 and &lt;= 100%</eaover>      <eadetcit>LF_110 (Refresh 2008) Existing Vegetation Cover</eadetcit>    </overview>  </eainfo>  <distinfo>    <distrib>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntpos>Wildland Fire Science, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center, U.S. Geological Survey</cntpos>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>          <address>USGS EROS</address>          <city>Sioux Falls</city>          <state>SD</state>          <postal>57198</postal>          <country>US</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>605/594-6151</cntvoice>        <cntemail>webmapping@usgs.gov</cntemail>        <hours>0800 - 1600, CT M-F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</hours>        <cntinst>The USGS point of contact is for questions relating only to the data display and download from this web site. For questions regarding data content and quality, refer to the original metadata document.</cntinst>      </cntinfo>    </distrib>    <distliab>This product is reproduced from geospatial information prepared by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service and USGS EROS. By removing the contents of this package or taking receipt of these files via electronic file transfer methods, you understand that the data stored on this media is in draft condition. Represented features may not be in an accurate geographic location. The Forest Service and USGS EROS make no expressed or implied warranty, including warranty of merchantability and fitness, with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the data or their appropriateness for any user's purposes. The Forest Service and USGS EROS reserve the right to correct, update, modify, or replace this geospatial information without notification.</distliab>    <stdorder>      <digform>        <digtinfo>          <formname>ARCG</formname>          <formvern>ArcGIS 9.3</formvern>          <formspec>Raster</formspec>          <transize>42.886</transize>        </digtinfo>        <digtopt>          <onlinopt>            <computer>              <networka>                <networkr>http://landfire.cr.usgs.gov/viewer</networkr>              </networka>            </computer>          </onlinopt>        </digtopt>      </digform>      <fees>None</fees>      <turnarnd>Variable</turnarnd>    </stdorder>    <availabl>      <timeinfo>        <rngdates>          <begdate>20100101</begdate>          <enddate>unknown</enddate>        </rngdates>      </timeinfo>    </availabl>  </distinfo>  <metainfo>    <metd>20070201</metd>    <metc>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntpos>Customer Service Representative</cntpos>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>          <address>USGS EROS</address>          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>          <city>Sioux Falls</city>          <state>SD</state>          <postal>57198-0001</postal>          <country>US</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>605/594-6151</cntvoice>        <cnttdd>605/594-6933</cnttdd>        <cntfax>605/594-6589</cntfax>        <cntemail>custserv@usgs.gov</cntemail>        <hours>0800 - 1600 CT, M - F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</hours>      </cntinfo>    </metc>    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>    <mettc>local time</mettc>    <metsi>      <metscs>None</metscs>      <metsc>Unclassified</metsc>      <metshd>None</metshd>    </metsi>  </metainfo></metadata>